# Lokendra Singh Chouhan

Senior QA Specialist

lokendra91@gmail.com 🔀

+91 955 252 8557

Pune (

26 September, 1991

linkedin.com/in/lokendra91 in

github.com/lokendra9009 🕠

With over 6 Years of Industry experience, an eye for innovation and my inquisitive nature, I aspire to be involved in work where I can utilise my skills creatively & effectively contribute towards organisation's and my personal growth.

## **SKILLS**



# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior QA Specialist

**Nuance Communications** 

03/2017 – Present Pune, Maharastra, India

- Achievements/Tasks

- Building BDD Test automation framework for application under test using Cucumber Python and Java.
- Maintenance and Expansion of automated test cases in automation framework Evaluation of various test automation framework.
   Doubled the test cases count keeping the execution time almost same.
- Continuous Integration of Test Framework using Jenkins.
- Written automated scripts for Image Comparison and Audio Comparison that saved 19 man hours per month.
- OWASP Top 10 and security testing of web applications.
- Interacted and conducted demo of innovations done within project to share the idea across whole team.

# Graduate Test Engineer Imagination Technologies

09/2015 - 03/2017

Tasks

- Tested GPU driver on Linux for NWS & Xorg windowing system.
- Executed 80-100% test plans including Unit Test, Performance test, Stability test.
- Created Test cases, defect tracking, defect triaging.
- Prepared Test execution script using python/shell to completely automated unit test execution.
- Created Test deliverable documentations.
- Conducted Training Sessions for team to provide clarity on various functionalities.

Pune, Maharastra, India

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Software Test Engineer

#### Amdocs

07/2013 – 07/2015 Pune, Maharastra, India

- Tasks
- Executed End to End flows for Amdocs CRM. OMS & other retail frontends web application.
- Executed End to End Test scenarios involving Smoke testing, Regression testing, New Functionality testing.
- Reported, Managed & Triaged multiple severity 1 and 2 defects on daily basis.
- Interacted with Business Analysis team and other stakeholders for smooth delivery of application under test.
- Created scripts using Selenium Webdriver and Autoit for automating redundant jobs.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Automation Selenium Webdriver, Autoit, Sikuli Languages Java, Python

OS Win XP, Vista, 7, 8.1, Linux, OS X Versioning Tool Perforce, Git

**Testing Tools** HP ALM, QC, Bugzilla, Rally, TestRail, Jira, **Languages** Java, Python

qTest

**Web** HTML, XML, Javascripts, Bootstrap 2.0,

Technologies CSS

## **CERTIFICATES**

ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level (ITB0061996)

Automate The Boring Stuff With Python Programming

(UC-YM41OAOG)

Introduction to Python for Data Science - Microsoft DIPLOME D'ETUDES EN LANGUE FRANCAISE DELF A1 (4T2016) (Microsoft and edX) (French) (091755001704)

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor Of Engineering (Computer Science)

Acropolis Institute Of Technology and Research, Indore

2009 – 2013 68.04%

## 12th AISSE (CBSE)

**Emerald Heights International School** 

2008 – 2009 62.60%

### **LANGUAGES**

English French Hindi Marathi

Full Professional Proficiency Limited Working Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency Limited Working Proficiency